hey guys my name is Vojta Jina and i wanna show you Karma
Javascript Test Runner that we build to make Angular development more fun
because we xxxx in js TDD a lot
and we didn't want to use mocha from node.js
because Angular does a lot DOM manipulation
So to be sure that all these things work across all the different browsers
we really want you execute a test on real browsers
and that's exactly what testacular(Karma) does
it runs JavaScript code in real browsers as well as
any other devices such as your phone and tablet
to the perpose of this tut is to test you javascript code during devlopment
or as a part of continous integration
install Testacular(Karma) actuallyis pretty simple
Karma的安装其实非常的简单
I assume you already have node.js
if don't have,
just go to nodejs.org
and get from there this should be pretty straight forward
and then go to command line and just type
npm install -g testicular which will install testicular into your global
node module folder
it's more likely you will need to sudo execute this command
NPM is just the package manager for node.js
it comes bundled together with node.js if you have node.js probably have
NPM as well
and here we go
you have testicular
so let's grab Angular tutorial
and let's round its unit test using testicular(Karma)
there's only one thing we need and that's a simple configuration file
to recommend you to grab this example config file from github
to download this thing
and
its I'm opening the project of tut
here's the config file
that downloaded from github and the first option is
interesting for us is the
files array and that's where you
tell testicular which files you wanna know so you can see you can use these
wild character
and these files are basically
they can be either absolute path or they can be relative path
in which case resolve this path on this bashPath
and this basePath again can be
an absolute path or
it can be relative path on in which case it's gonna be resolved this
to location all this file all configuation file
so in our case we can keep this blank
and let's move on
to autoWatch ,autoWatch is true
that's really important as well because
thats tells testacular to watch all the files
and whenever you change any of those files it will execute all the test
and let's see
the last one browsers. let's put ChromeCanary in there
and that means that one
testacular is being started it will automatic be captured chrome Canada as well
and there is there's a bunch of other options but these are pretty much
default values just so that you can see what avaiable
options
but we don't need then now
so let's go backto command line and start testacular
we are passing one argument which is path to the config file
you can see and it automaticly started chrome
and i will go to filters for example, and i press save
all the unit tests are executed immediately
so this is a
simple filtered and basically converts boolean value
into utf8 character which is a
cross if it's false and it's a check
if it's true so let's say we want to
extend his behavior to
to return a question mark if the values undefined
and then open the related unit test
you can see we are using now Jasmine
which is an awesome testing framework
and  testacular is just a test runner
as it's not a testing framework so you can use
pretty much
any test framework you like
we like Jasmine so so we are using Jasmine
it should convert undefined
to question mark
expect undefined
to be converted to question
now we go we have failing unit test
so do that let me show you something
first let me show you dump
because you can you dump and
it will dump the value into termimal which is pretty cool because
all these things that's happening real browser
there is a ChromeCanary so you can actually go to console
if you like you can use console.log
let me show you that.
and you can see anything
beacuase yeah because unfortunately in
current version of Chrome
there's no consle so let's use
console.log
and there you go undefined
so if you like use console you can do that but
and thing is pretty cool if you can stay in your text editor as much as possible
and that's when dump is really helpful okay
so let's implement this super killer feature
angular if is undefined
I mean if input is undefine just return '?'
there you go and
it works. awesome.
this is how you can use Karma from command line
which is pretty cool because that means
you can use that
any texteditor you like I mean I've been
using it in sublime
which is awesome but really there is no
special support from sublime so if you
want use it with save
in vim you can do that
.
and when I saved the file
the tests are executed if I comment down
this line our unit test is failing
I'm bring it back it's back
cool soon the last thing
I'm gonna kill testicular and you can
see that
the browser has been killed as well
to run karma from webstorm
we need to create their run configuration tool and click here
edit configurations and we add node.js configuration
let's call it  testacular server
and really this is just a name so you
can pick up anything you like
after now  thats a
that's kind of silly but this needs to be
an absolute path
to node.js binary. Working
directory
this is ok.  this is the  project folder
and path to node.js App
that again needs to be an absolute path
to karma
so you can see amusing nvm which is
really nice
strips for managing multiple versions of
node if you're not using in NVM and
this gonna be probably
something like /usr/local/bin/node/karma
and application parameters
we need to pass the configuration file
in this case you're going to execute
angularJS unit test so we're going to pass
angularFiles.js
.
let's create one more configuration because this time
I wanna show you different mean of
triggering the tests.
we are not going to watch the files but, we're going to trigger the test manually
soon let's creat 'karma run'
again "path to node", that's
the absolute path to nodejs binary
"working directory" in some current
project folder
and "path to node app"  that's going to be
testicular-run
apply and you're all set .
before we start testicular let me show you AuglarFiles.js
because that's the test configuration file
you can see there's a bunch of files at the end
of the file there is autoWatch is true
so let's change it to false
I mean if you like
you can use true to to watched the files
But i want to show you differently
and browsers thats  ChromeCanary, let's use chrome
stable as well and we do
testacular server let's start to server
let's open source code
and I do change and save the file and
nothing happens
because we are not watching the files so
you need to trigger the
run manually, let's do "karma run"
and there you go you execute all angular unit test which is over
go where 1500 unit test in each browsers
okay let's let's fail something
let's comment out this line that should felt something
there you go be and this is
really good about webstorm because there
is this
error and you can see this is a
clickable link so you can click
this guy and it will open the file
an directly go to correct line
which is really cool and this case
I thought it's super useful but
imagine something I'm think usefull and
split this guy
and lets let's just executed this
failing unit test we use iit to individual executives just this unit test
and let's refactor this a little bit
we extract this into
of mergeHead and let's throw
an error here
we execute
this unit is again and there you go
there's a full call stack
and I'll all these links are clickable
links
so there's a call to
angular forEach you wanna see that
just click this link
and there you go we are inside the ... I'm
sorry it was different
yeah this one and we are in different file
inside forEach definition which is
super cool
I mean this is really great about webstorm
through this you can see this function
you want to see the definitions this
come on click this function
and there you go I mean webstorm really understand JavaScript
and that's cool okay guys
so this was testicular with webstorm
to debug from webstorm we need to
create the debug configuration
so let's edit the configuartion and
add javascript debug
let's call it Karma debug
URL http://localhost:8080/debug.html
you can pick Chrome or Firefox
and set this remote URL to
your local
angurlar project of like this
apply and you're all set so let's run
to server first
and one say
we want to debug this unit test all over there
so we use iit to execute just as one unit test
and let's put the breakpoint here
let's do karma debug
and here you can see webstorm starts
this chrome and there you go
yes very much all the debugging tools
that you would have
if you were debugging in chrome
but this has advantage that you have
nice code highlighting and
you have easy navigation between files
like you see forEach
just come on and
click and there you go you are inside forEach
right, so let's debug this unit test
let's watch parsed.key
which is undefined at this point
step into this function so you can see it
still undefined that now
we already parsed the first header , so it's 'a'
let's do next
let's step into
and there you go it's "a, b"
so you get it
cool
One Note if you want to debug again
it's easy to go to  browser and fresh that
instead of restarting the browser so we
can see
we are debugging again so you can again
step into and stuff like that okay guys
so this was debug from  webstorm and
thank you very much for watching